Carl Soriano

+1 (306) 750-3221 • Calgary, AB • carljohng.soriano@gmail.com

Software engineering student seeking to gain experience and skills through an internship this summer to further progress my career and knowledge in my profession.

SKILLS

• Technical Skills: MicrosoftOS, MacOS, Office 365, Teams, Zoom.

Experience with working with the Microsoft System and as well as Mac. Have worked with Word, Excel and Powerpoint on various school projects. Worked with Teams and Zoom throughout the school semester.

• Computer-Aided Design: AutoCAD, and Fusion360.

Had the opportunity to take drafting all throughout high school in which we used AutoCAD as our platform to create multiple designs such as tables and screws. Worked with Fusion360 in first-year university to design working/rotating objects.

• Languages: Basic knowledge of Python, Currently in pursuit of learning HTML and CSS.

Worked with Python3 in first year to create basic codes to set the foundation in programming. Presently, learning both HTML and CSS to build into my software engineering career.

Team Oriented	Numercy	Time and Organization
Work Ethic	Communication	Multilinglingual

EDUCATION

University of Calgary Bachelor of Science and Faculty of Engineering Year 2. Specialization in Software (SWE). 2020 - Present

Swift Current Comprehensive High School | Grades 9 - 12

Graduated June 2020

EXPERIENCE

Team Leader Sales Associate

Volcom Chinook | Calgary, AB

Jan. 2022 – Present

Currently holds the position of a Part-Time Team Leader Sales Associate at Volcom Chinook.

- Provides high-quality customer service to optimize customer purchasing and the payment process via POS cash register
- Responsibility for managing closing operations for late-night shifts
- Regularly completes the setup, breakdown, and product preparation for promotional displays and in-store demonstrations
- Educates customers on available product options to meet and exceed customer service experience expectations
- Stands for long periods of time, using ladders, and lifting boxes
- Assists with overall store operations and upkeep

Roughneck May. 2021 – Aug. 2021

Diamond Energy Services | Swift Current, SK

Experienced working as a roughneck in the oil-field industry.

Connecting and disconnecting of drill string using hydraulic-powered tongs, drill bits, drill collars racking back drill pipe into
slots located on the board in the derrick, and setting test pumps downhole in a timely manner safely and efficiently for
contractors and customers.

- Keep daily logs of mud weight and viscosity levels for the driller.
- Loading and unloading drill pipe onto and from pipe racks and staged areas containing tools, drill bits, drill collars, and elevators using a front-end loader.
- Responsible for Rigging up and rigging down anytime the rig has completed and serviced the well.

Grocery Store Clerk

June. 2018 – Aug. 2020

Safeway | Swift Current, SK

Had the position of a personable Safeway Store Clerk who worked quickly and efficiently while providing outstanding guest service in a fast-paced setting. Knowledge of proper bagging techniques, Safeway layout inventory, and store standards Exceptional interpersonal and communication skills leading to robust relationships with co-workers, store leaders, customers, and the community.

- Perform sales floor work, such as greeting or assisting customers, stocking shelves, or taking inventory.
- Operate POS cash register confidently and efficiently, including payment by cash, cheques, credit cards, vouchers, or automatic
 debits and issued receipts, refunds, credits, or change.
- Confer with customers by telephone or in-person to provide information about products or services, take orders, or obtain details of complaints.
- Stock shelves, racks, cases, bins, and tables with new or transferred merchandise, and verified merchandise
- Customer Service